Women's Studies Association of British Columbia fonds
Simon Fraser University Archives and Records Management Department
Women's Studies Association of British Columbia fonds
1974 - 1980
F-75
Q101243154
25 cm of textual records
Simon Fraser University Archives and Records Management Department Maggie Benston Student Services Building, Rm. 0400 8888 University Dr. Burnaby British Columbia Canada V5A 1S6 Telephone: 778.782.3805 Email: archives@sfu.ca http://www.sfu.ca/archives
Women's Studies Association of British Columbia
The Women's Studies Association of British Columbia was a province-wide organization set up in 1974 to improve women's social status through the promotion, continuation and development of women'studies programmes at the post-secondary level of education and at adult community education centres. Soon afterwards, the association expanded to include high-school women's studies curricula. On December 11, 1978 the association incorporated as a society; it disbanded in 1980 due to declining support and lack of representation by members from colleges and universities.
The objectives of the Women's Studies Association were to promote women's studies in the province; to encourage research into previously unexamined aspects of Canadian women's lives, with particular emphasis on BC; to establish adequate support services for women at all post-secondary institutions throughout the province; and, to ensure that women's studies remained a part of the women's movement and that staff and students involved in women's studies were familiar with the aims and objectives of the women's movement.
A standing committee consisting of a coordinator, a secretary, a treasurer, a communications organizer, and a member-at-large directed the association. Membership included students and faculty from the province's community colleges and universities, persons from community service groups, and people with an individual interest in women's studies.
published
Full
Revised
Title of the fonds is based on its provenance.
The fonds consists of records created and received by the Women's Studies Association of British Columbia in carrying out its objectives. Includes constitution and by-laws, minutes, correspondence, conference registration forms, conference minutes, papers, membership lists, and publications.
The materials were arranged by the Archivist.
Women
Unknown.
All accessions have been processed as of September 2002. No further accruals are expected.
See file F-37-4-0-17 in the Margo Dunn Collection (F 37).
Some files may contain personal or confidential information. Access to these files may be restricted as stipulated by Archives policy or the donor. Files marked 'pending review' must be reviewed by an archivist prior to release, and as a result of the review access restrictions may apply. Please see the file lists and consult the archivist for more details.
A file list is available.
- Constitution and Bylaws, 1974 - 1977; F-75-0-0-0-1 (Archival box - standard 75-1)
  published
  Textual records
  Pending review
- Minutes, 1976 - 1980; F-75-0-0-0-2 (Archival box - standard 75-1)
- Correspondence, 1975 - 1978; F-75-0-0-0-3 (Archival box - standard 75-1)
- Correspondence, 1978; F-75-0-0-0-4 (Archival box - standard 75-1)
- Correspondence, 1979; F-75-0-0-0-5 (Archival box - standard 75-1)
- Correspondence, 1980; F-75-0-0-0-6 (Archival box - standard 75-1)
- Conference papers, 1974; F-75-0-0-0-7 (Archival box - standard 75-1)
- Conference papers, 1975; F-75-0-0-0-8 (Archival box - standard 75-1)
- Conference papers, 1976; F-75-0-0-0-9 (Archival box - standard 75-1)
- Conference papers, 1976; F-75-0-0-0-10 (Archival box - standard 75-1)
- Conference papers, 1977; F-75-0-0-0-11 (Archival box - standard 75-1)
- Conference papers, 1977; F-75-0-0-0-12 (Archival box - standard 75-1)
- Conference papers, 1977; F-75-0-0-0-13 (Archival box - standard 75-1)
- Conference papers, 1978; F-75-0-0-0-14 (Archival box - standard 75-2)
- Conference papers, 1978; F-75-0-0-0-15 (Archival box - standard 75-2)
- Conference papers, 1978; F-75-0-0-0-16 (Archival box - standard 75-2)
- Conference papers, 1979; F-75-0-0-0-17 (Archival box - standard 75-2)
- Conference papers, 1979; F-75-0-0-0-18 (Archival box - standard 75-2)
- Conference papers, 1980; F-75-0-0-0-19 (Archival box - standard 75-2)
- Membership lists, 1976 - 1978; F-75-0-0-0-20 (Archival box - standard 75-2)
- Publications and Newsletters, 1975 - 1979; F-75-0-0-0-21 (Archival box - standard 75-2)
  Open